<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Domain Controller on naut&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.nazaretyan.com/tags/domain-controller/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Domain Controller on naut&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <managingEditor>moushegh@gmail.com (Moushegh Nazaretyan)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>moushegh@gmail.com (Moushegh Nazaretyan)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.nazaretyan.com/tags/domain-controller/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>how to connect windows 2008R2 to windows 2003R2 Domain controller</title>
      <link>https://www.nazaretyan.com/post/how-to-connect-windows-2008r2-to-windows-2003r2-domain-controller/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>moushegh@gmail.com (Moushegh Nazaretyan)</author>
      <guid>https://www.nazaretyan.com/post/how-to-connect-windows-2008r2-to-windows-2003r2-domain-controller/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Few days ago i get a chance to configure new windows 2008R2 on already working infrastructure with windows2003R2,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;main goad was to create RODC (read only domain controller) within AD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after starting the project i get few real interesting situations that want to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;we need windows 2003R2 with domain controller role on it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;we need to install windows 2008R2 on separate machine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after we need to connect windows 2008R2 to our infrastracture as usual host. login on it with domain administrator account and install DNS role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after DNS is installed we need to run DCPROMO (it will install all nessary roles for domain conntroler). seems everything easy but after few next&amp;#8217;s win2008 will tell you that you need to prepair windows2003 for migration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;what we need to do in this case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;we need to put win2008 disk to win2003 machine. and copy directory (in support) adprep to C:\ ,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after we need to go to C:\adprep (in CMD) and run one for the file ( for your machine ARCH) for me it was 64 bit version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;command is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;adprep.exe /forestPrep&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;it will tell you that its going to update schema  of  2003 to newer version&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOW TIP , you need to PUSH &amp;#8220;C&amp;#8221; and only after ENTER button, in other case it will give you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;0x4 error :))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after pushing C and ENTER it will work on your domain like 3-4 minutes. and  will report you that domain is ready for migration&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but you need to run here one more command&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;adprep /domainPrep,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;if it will work fine means that your DC working on NATIVE mode if not you need to go to Acitve directory and user settings and RISE your domain till 2003 version.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after RISING domain version you need to run one more time /domainPrep command. and it will finish without problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;now we need to rin adprep /rodcprep it will make RODC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;after all this steps done, you can return to windows2008 and finish DCPROMO steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one restart and your windows 2008R2 is in working infrastructure of windows 2003r2 as secondary domain controller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;one more tip &amp;#8211; if errors will continue apper &amp;#8211; try adprep /&lt;em&gt;noFileCopy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;and add your user to shchema-administrators group.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>